# Chris Ridder Beaverton, OR

512-619-6724 / cjridder@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/chrisridder

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Architectural Engineering Construction (AEC) Leader with 20+ years' experience across verticals. Trusted advisor to leadership and key stakeholders, analyzing processes and eliminating barriers that impact end-users. Track record of streamlining and optimizing business operations, increasing efficiency, and driving revenue. Demonstrated success researching the impact of new technology on legacy processes, presenting implementation and training solutions that generate quantifiable, impressive results.

# PROJECT EXPERIENCE

- **Discipline:** Architecture, Audio/Visual, Commissioning, Construction Administration, Electrical, Interiors, LEED, Mechanical, Networking, Plumbing, Process Piping, Security, Structural, Telecommunications
- Industry: Assisted Living, Athletics, Bond Planning, Commercial Correctional, Data Centers, Education (K-12), Healthcare, Higher Education, Hospitality, Institutional, Master Planning, Mixed-Use, Multi-Family, Office, Residential, Retail, Workplace

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Industry: Building Information Modeling (BIM), Virtual Design and Construction (VDC)
- Autodesk: Revit Implementation, Revit Architecture (MEP, Structure 2008-2021), BIM360, Navisworks, AutoCAD 12-2021, AutoCAD Architecture (MEP 2004-2021), Deployments, Network License Administration, Point Layout
- **Production:** PropertyWizard, Unifi, Keynote Manager, Revizto, ArchVision RPC, Enscape, Bonus Tools, RTV Xporter PRO, Ideate BIMLink, Ideate Sticky, Ideate Explorer, Ideate Apps, RushForth Tools
- Programming: AutoCAD CUI, AutoLISP, AutoHotkey, Dynamo, Git, VisualLISP, Python, pyRevit
- Office: Google Workspace, Microsoft Office, Asana, Microsoft Teams, Slack, Zoom, Newforma, TonicDM, Pinnacle Series, WordPress, SharePoint, Workflowy
- OS: Windows, macOS, Ubuntu

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **TEECOM**

11/2018 - 6/2020, 2/2021 - Present

TEECOM works with property owners, architects, engineers, and contractors to design and implement integrated, efficient, and user-friendly systems.

# Senior BIM Specialist

- Provide quality control and quality assurance, reviewing project standards throughout various phases, adhering to client project requirements and industry best practices.
- Partner with corporate staff to deploy project-specific templates, ensuring adherence to plans.
- Focusing on employee engagement and development, designing and administering in-depth customized training, and bolstering skillsets.
- Key projects & accomplishments include:
  - o Created BIM360 standards for data center multi-building projects that used multiple versions of Revit for each building.
    - Allowed team members to find and update projects quickly.

BIM Designs, Inc. 8/2020 – 12/2020

BIM Designs is a preconstruction technology firm offering turnkey BIM modeling, laser scanning, coordination management, and other VDC solutions. **Project Manager** 

- Trusted advisor to clients, designing and executing projects from ideation to post-implementation support.
- Coordinated workflow, ensuring appropriate adherence to plan design and goals while keeping stakeholders updated and satisfied and resolving any issues.

Mazzetti 5/2017 – 11/2018

Mazzetti consultants deliver world-class MEP engineering and technology solutions, aiding clients in designing, optimizing, and equipping environments. **Regional VDC Manager** 

- Implemented third-party applications allowing end-users to design projects according to standards, increasing productivity.
- Trained staff on TonicDM and Microsoft Teams.
- Key projects & accomplishments include:
  - o Spearheaded the conversion process of >600 CAD standard details to Revit drafting views.
    - Eliminated all AutoCAD elements. Increased productivity and decreased errors, boosting ROI.

GBD Architects 2/2015 – 5/2017

GBD is an interdisciplinary architecture, urban design, interior design, and space planning firm.

#### BIM Manager

- Led the firm's renewed implementation efforts, standards development and documentation, and standard content and processes.
- Key projects & accomplishments include:
  - o Designed and launched a monthly interactive training program.
    - Established a baseline of knowledge and standards compliance for >20 end-users.
  - Created turnkey AutoCAD and Revit deployments and upgrades ready for production with minimal end-user interaction.

SSOE Group 8/2014 – 2/2015

SSOE provides quality project solutions to the semiconductor, automotive, food, chemical, glass, manufacturing, healthcare, power, and general building industries. BIM Project Specialist

- Provided customized training to colleagues based on project needs.
- Key projects & accomplishments include:
  - o Improved Autodesk Revit content development for semiconductor process piping systems.
    - Made accurate information more readily available, increasing productivity.

# Topcon Solutions Store fka PPI Group

12/2012 - 8/2014

Topcon Positioning Group designs, manufactures, and distributes precision measurement and workflow solutions for the global construction, geospatial, and agriculture markets. PPI Group, a Topcon Solutions Store, is a value-added reseller of Autodesk software solutions.

### Applications Specialist & Autodesk Certified Instructor/Product Support Professional

- Trusted advisor to firms, providing technical support, consultation, and training through the implementation process.
- Provided sales support for technical presentations to prospective and established clients.
- Key projects & accomplishments include:
  - o Developed a custom curriculum to solve client-specific training needs defined by their workflow.

O'Connell Robertson 3/2000 – 11/2012

O'Connell Robertson is a full-service architecture, engineering, and interior design firm.

#### BIM Manager

- Provided turnkey AutoCAD and Revit deployments and upgrades ready for production with minimal end-user interaction.
- Key projects & accomplishments include:
  - o Led Revit implementation from 2007-2012 for a multi-discipline firm with multiple locations.
  - o Supported >60 Revit projects from 2007-2012.
  - o Developed and launched a monthly interactive training program.
    - Established a knowledge and standards compliance baseline for >20 end-users across 2 offices.

#### **EDUCATION / CERTIFICATIONS**

# **AUTODESK CERTIFICATIONS:**

Autodesk Certified Instructor (ACI); Consulting; Marketing; Product Support; Advanced Specialization: MEP Engineering Systems for Technical Representatives, Structural Engineering for Technical Representatives, and Building Construction for Technical Representatives; AEC Building Certification for Technical Representatives

### **REVIT CERTIFICATIONS:**

Revit Architecture Certified Professional; MEP Certified Professional; Structure Certified Professional

Associate of Applied Science, Engineering Design Graphics, Austin Community College Courses Completed, Interior Architecture, Kansas State University

### PUBLICATIONS AND PRESENTATIONS

**AARUG –** BIM Project kickoff Meeting Protocols (January 2012), Roof Drain Calculations, Symbols & Detailing (May 2012), Advanced Scheduling (September 2012)

**PdxRUG** – Revit Project Model Planning Checklist (March 2013)

SeaRUG - Good Content Needs Great Organization (November 2013)

GitHub - Clear local BIM360 cache (September 2019), Set workset1 current on open (December 2019)

Cadalyst - Lumber blocks (August 2003)